<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SCI 2000 - Winter 2021</title>
    <link>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/</link>
    <description>Recent content on SCI 2000 - Winter 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Problems</title>
      <link>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/practice/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of practice problems. The problem numbers refer to the 6thedition of Applied Multivariate Statistical Analysis by Johnson &amp;amp; Wichern. A copy has been put on course reserve through the Science Library.
Chapter 3&amp;ndash;Sample Geometry and Random Sampling #  3.8, 3.9, 3.10, 3.14, 3.15, 3.17
Chapter 4&amp;ndash;The Multivariate Normal Distribution #  4.3, 4.4, 4.4, 4.5, 4.6, 4.7, 4.8, 4.16, 4.18, 4.19, 4.21, 4.22
Chapter 5&amp;ndash;Inferences about a Mean Vector #  5.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/slides/</guid>
      <description>Slides #  If you are registered for the course, you can find the material on UM Learn.
Some of these slides borrow heavily from other sources. In particular, I would like to acknowledge R for Data Science and Rafael Irizarry&amp;rsquo;s notes on data visualization.
 Course overview Summary statistics Data visualization Principles of effective visualization) Linear regression  Residual analysis More examples   Relational data  Mutating joins Filtering joins RDBMS   Text data  Regular expressions Sentiment analysis   Web scraping  More scraping examples Scraping with XPath APIs   Logistic regression Automating data analysis tasks  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary Material</title>
      <link>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/suppl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://maxturgeon.ca/w21-sci2000/suppl/</guid>
      <description>Supplementary Material #  On this page, I will post additional resources and supplementary material for the course.
Resources for R #  In this course, we will use R as the main computational tool. Below are some resources:
 R for Data Science by Grolemund and Wickham. Hands-On Programming with R by Grolemund. Jenny Bryan&amp;rsquo;s course on Data wrangling, exploration, and analysis with R  In particular, I recommend the notes on The Many Flavours of R objects   Mine Cetinkaya&amp;rsquo;s curated list of resources for R If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a deep understanding of R, I recommend Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s book Advanced R RStudio has several great cheatsheets on their website.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>